在上一次讲座中，我们讨论了机器人关节控制，这就是问题所在
In the last lecture we talked about robot joint control and that’s the problem of
我们如何控制驱动机器人手臂关节角度的电机。
how do we control the motor which is actuating the joint angle in a robot arm.
现在在一个真正的机器人中，这个控制问题比我们谈论的要复杂一点
Now in a real robot, this control problem is a little bit more complicated than we talked
在最后一个讲座中，一个非常简单的例子可以说清楚。
about in the last lecture and a pretty simple example can make that clear.
如果你考虑控制我肩关节的问题，那么我的手臂的重量，
If you consider in the problem of controlling my shoulder joint, then the weight of my arm,
作用在这个臂上的重力将在我的肩膀上施加一个扭矩，所以手臂就是这样
gravity acting on this arm is going to exert a torque on my shoulder and so the arm is
想要摔倒，所以这是我手臂上的肌肉，必须采用相反的方式
going to want to fall down, so it’s the muscles in my arm, have to apply an opposite
扭矩，以保持我的手臂水平。因此，机器人手臂控制中一个非常重要的因素
torque in order to keep my arm horizontal. So, a really important factor in robot arm control
是重力的影响，重力作用于机器人手臂的各个环节。
is the influence of gravity, the weight force that acts on the various links of a robot’s arm.
现在，另一个问题是惯性的变化。正在驱动的电机
Now, another problem is to do with the change in inertia. The motor, which is driving, for
例如，我的肩关节看到了电机本身的惯性，但它也看到了
instance my shoulder joint sees the inertia of the motor itself, but it also sees the
这种联系的惯性，所以为了加速这一点，将不得不加速这一切
inertia of this link, so in order to accelerate this, going to have to accelerate all this
我的手臂的一部分，需要在电机中增加额外的扭矩
part of my arm and that requires additional torque in the motor in order to
实现特定的加速度;它是我手臂惯性的函数。
achieve a particular acceleration; it’s a function of the inertia of my arm.
现在，惯性取决于我的手臂的配置。我的手臂在这里有最大的惯性
Now, the inertia depends on the configuration of my arm. My arm here is got maximum inertia
关于肩轴，但如果手臂处于这样的配置，那就得到了
about the shoulder axis, but if the arm was in a configuration like this, it’s got
惯性较小。如果它是这样的配置，它的惯性仍然较小。
less inertia. If it was in a configuration like this, it’s got less inertia still.
因此，从特定关节向外的链接的配置将受到影响
So, the configuration of the links outwards from a particular joint are going to affect
那个关节看到的惯性。所有这些影响，重力问题
the inertia that that joint sees. So all of these sorts of effects, the gravity problem
惯性问题在我们称之为刚体动力效应的过程中被混为一谈
and the inertia problem are lumped together in what we call rigid body dynamic effects
这就是我们将在这个特定的讲座中谈论的内容。
and that’s what we’re going to talk about in this particular lecture.
现在，在上一个讲座中，我们提出了这个方块图，我们一直在努力完成所有工作
Now, in the last lecture, we put up this block diagram and we worked our way through all
图中的不同块。在这个讲座中，我们要做的是把它
the different blocks in the diagram. In this lecture, what we’re going to do is put the
关注机器人关节本身;这是一个关节与机器人手臂中的其他关节相互作用的地方。
spotlight on the robot joint itself; this is where one joint interacts with the other joints in the robot arm.
这就是改变重力和改变惯性的效果，这些都是机械效应，
This is where the effects like changing gravity and changing inertia, these are mechanic effects,
来自机器人关节，通过齿轮箱返回，它们影响机器人关节内的电机。
come from the robot joint, back through the gearbox and they influence the motor within the robot joint.
所以，这个讲座的目的是尝试解开其中的一些问题，
So, that’s the purpose of this lecture, is to try and unpack some of these issues,
看看这些重力问题和惯性效应如何影响个别电机
see how these gravity problems and the inertia effects, impact on the individual motors that
正在驾驶各个关节。
are driving the individual joints.
如果我们想要对机器人关节运动进行高质量控制，我们不能忽视这些效果。
We can’t ignore these effects if we want to do high quality control of robot joint motion.